

# BERTRAND GORGE **DIRECTOR OF PRODUCTS** bertrand.famille-gorge.org **J** 06 31 40 43 51

bertrand.gorge@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/bertrandgorge/

twitter.com/bertrandgorge



Experienced product manager with fifteen years of experience in web development. I ignited, led and managed several products from ideation to maturity, while accompanying the growth of CrossKnowledge Technology.

Father of four, concerned about the future of Earth and the life our children will have. Fascinated by the pace of change, new technologies, new issues, new paradygms. Hopeful of being able to have an impact.

I wish to join a growing team with a broad vision and the will to change things!



# **EDUCATION**

# Master 2 Executive Director, Management - Strategy ESSEC Business School (2016 - 2017)

Executive master on management and strategy. Final dissertation on Innovation Strategy in the specific context of a mature organization.

# Master of Engineering (M.Eng.) Computer Science ESIEE (1991-1997)

Engineering degree with focus on Computer Science.



Complex problem solving

Criticism Creativity Agile project management

Negociation

**Decision making** 



# INTERESTS

## **TED and Earth issues**

I'm a big fan of TED conferences, and I've watched hundreds of them (in plane transits). This is probably one of my main source of awareness about Global Warming and Earth protection.

## Management 3.0

I developed a real interest for all alternatives to top-down, classical management technics (holacracy, freedom-form companies, etc.). I follow the work of Jurgen Appelo, Isaac Getz, Valve, ... I have set up agile in my teams and have always loved to experiment people management.

# Myers Briggs Type Indicator - I'm an ESTP

I love MBTI and I find it very useful for teams to create trust and cohesion.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Director of Product Management**

## CrossKnowledge (2012-2018)

Managed the team of product management for all CrossKnowledge products, including strategy, user research, design, and marketing, with tight relationships with the development teams.

Active participation in the sell process, including prospective meetings with key accounts, speaking in events and sales strategy.

## **Director of R&D**

## CrossKnowledge (2009-2012)

Hired, organized and managed software development teams. I led the adoption of Scrum, as well as other quality and project management processes.

Led our flagship LMS product on the path to handle more than 10M learners, with more than 500 global clients.

Managed the technical side of the acquisition of Mohive software by CrossKnowledge in 2010, successfully driving the change of technology and software development teams, including cross-cultural relashionship management.

## **Founder**

# Epistema (2002-2009)

Co-founded Epistema and led its technical development, up to its acquisition by CrossKnowledge in 2008. Accompanied the growth of the structure from 2 people to 80 people in 2017, setting in place the technology foundations, processes and hiring.



## **Industry** awards

Proud of having CrossKnowledge products receiving many industry awards from Brandon Hall, 2elearning.com, TrainingIndustry.com and more.





